Do you want to take a break?
If you don't want to, I will continue to talk.
Wow, the coffee I drank is so bitter.
Next, we will focus on the suit part.
From now on, the most important part is how to make the suit jacket.
The front is all small appetizers.
Now is the core content.
First, let's import the reference picture.
For reference pictures, we can see that
when you add a background picture, you have to pay attention to the proportion.
How do we pay attention to the proportion?
Just looking at the waist,
it may be a little difficult.
Then you refer to the shoulder line.
How to refer to the shoulder line?
From the point below the night,
along the curve of your waist,
to the point of your arm,
go along here.
This is your shoulder line.
So in the picture,
is your shoulder line still a little short?
Right?
So you have to enlarge this proportion.
Let's change this proportion to 150.
Let's take a look again.
Now you go along this shoulder line.
How do we refer to this shoulder line?
This is the collar.
This point of the collar is close to your neck.
Then this point is the actual position of your shoulder line.
Then go here.
So this is how your shoulder line looks like.
We can also use this method to refer to the shoulder line when we identify this external reference picture.
Or you can look at this buckle.
It doesn't matter if you don't understand the collar.
Let's look at this buckle in another place.
Take a closer look.
Is there a buckle mark here?
The center of the buckle.
Because you must have a buckle.
Sometimes it will buckle.
Right?
After the buckle is buckled,
the center of the buckle is against the body of the person.
Then stick this shoulder to your shoulder.
Look here.
Is there a buckle mark here?
Do you understand?
You know how to buckle.
Here I reduce the transparency
to refer to the model of the human body.
Okay.
Then we can start to draw.
Pay attention when following the drawing.
First of all,
let's teach you how to identify this picture.
How to identify.
This is our suit.
Suit is any pattern.
Here at the very outside.
The thick line is the external line of the pattern.
You can draw along this external line of the pattern.
Then this thing is the line of the line.
Can you see it?
Then the pattern.
The pattern has a Chinese character on it.
The front is the front.
The back is the back.
The bottom of the page is the bottom of the page.
Understand?
So the suit sometimes has three pieces.
Sometimes there are four pieces.
You have to recognize it clearly.
Okay.
Then this.
This icon is to let you step along this line.
It has to be sewn together on the left.
But they are still a whole pattern.
Okay.
Uh.
Sometimes it may be divided into two panels.
It doesn't matter.
Okay.
Then this is this.
This is the divine path.
This is another divine path.
Right?
So why do we have the bottom of the page?
Because of the suit.
We want the suit to look like it.
There is no obvious bulge on the side.
So we will pin a panel in the middle.
And then.
In fact, this.
The bottom of this page.
It is the front and the back.
It will be combined with them at the same time.
And it is.
It is based on them.
To draw out.
So he actually hid some divine paths in the middle.
So when we draw.
You have to pay attention.
You.
When you hook it down.
It's in.
Because there is a divine path here.
Because the bottom of the page is an independent panel.
Okay.
This is a god.
And then there's a god here.
See.
But this god.
You see.
He recognized this panel like this.
Just.
You think.
Do we have a tight waist here?
It's tight.
But.
The bottom is here.
It will be.
Is the person's curve.
Is it tight first?
Then protrude.
So you are following this.
When the panel is hooked.
He has to tighten it first.
Then protrude.
Understand?
He is also like this.
Tighten first.
Then protrude.
He is not like this.
You have to recognize.
So.
Here.
Then.
He didn't walk here.
He will protrude.
So.
There will be an intersection in the middle.
Part of the overlap.
So.
You see.
Can you understand?
In fact, it is to match the curve of the human body.
Then the pocket.
Why does the pocket open in this position?
Because our god.
God here.
He.
Well.
The last part will be cut here.
So there will be a cut in the middle.
Just put the pocket.
To block this.
This is the middle.
That's the middle.
You see.
The middle.
That's the middle.
There is a gap.
You see.
So when we got the piece.
We will get it here.
And then the next section.
Individually.
Then I put the pocket.
At the end .
Is the seam of this.
It is on the line of cut off.
Then we have heard it now.
Definitely feel very tired.
Isn't it?
It feels like a little bit of trouble.
It's okay.
After this lesson.
After I finish uploading the video.
I will upload the file directly in the copy file.
I will also upload the file in the copy file.
I will post it on the webpage.
I will post it on the website.
The file will be sent to you directly in the document,
which is the file that I have saved.
At that time, you can do it directly with the live version.
You don't have to study what the principle is.
As long as you know that it is almost this form, you can do it.
Even more, you can open our modular controller.
There is a live suit in it.
You can take a set out of it directly.
Let's skip these steps.
Here, my collar is here,
because later we will be involved in the transformation of the collar.
So I cut off the collar separately and didn't sew it to the top of the body.
So when you get the file, it will look like this.
Here is the collar.
Re-activate first.
Okay.
Then,
we will sew the normal part first.
First, arrange the file well.
Then, arrange the value so that the file does not cross too much and is far from the body.
Then, put the back here.
Remember to open the texture surface.
Why open the texture surface?
If you are a novice in Mildness Designer,
you should pay attention to the file.
When you sew,
you should sew the front to the outside.
You can't sew the back to the outside.
If you sew the back to the outside,
the file is not sewn correctly.
So,
yes,
the Mildness Designer is right.
We do this to distinguish the correct way.
Then, we will use the sewing tool
to sew the two parts together.
If you want to sew one part and multiple parts,
remember to press the Shift key to sew.
You can do it like this in my video,
like this.
Sew one part at a time.
After sewing,
sew the side here as well.
And sew the back here as well.
Okay, let's sew it first.
Wait a minute.
You will find that the sleeve is missing.
Where is the sleeve?
First of all,
usually,
the reference picture you get has a sleeve.
If I don't have a sleeve here,
I will show you later.
When you get the version,
or when you adjust it yourself,
what if you don't have a sleeve?
We will see later.
So I don't have a sleeve here.
Of course,
you don't have to worry about it.
You will know when you follow me later.
Then,
when we have simulated here,
is it because we didn't add a button here in the front?
It will spread out,
so we will press the W key to click on the version.
Then,
stack the version here first.
Stack it up.
Fix it with a fixed needle.
Then,
let's add a button.
For the position of the button,
I am here,
in fact,
according to my own habits,
I almost referred to it.
How did I refer to it here?
This is a thread,
and this point is what I drew along the picture just now.
OK.
Yes.
Then,
use the button to put it in place.
The loop is round.
It won't deal with language.
I used to deal with it,
but because I have to do this kind of live broadcast for a long time now,
I think everyone will understand it better.
So,
I won't do it later.
Well.
OK.
Then,
after we have this button,
choose it to be symmetrical to the symmetrical version.
In fact,
we did it before.
I used to record a live broadcast,
and then do the teaching video again.
But,
but there are too few people who watch the teaching video.
So now we will,
well,
I also save a little.
Everyone also looks at it carefully.
Just do this long live broadcast.
And the time is a little later.
Everyone has time to watch.
Then we use this button to put the button and the button to put together.
Well,
after putting them together,
we can select this fixed pin,
delete all fixed pins.
OK.
Now,
we are almost done with the main version of this big body,
right?
Well,
here,
because I use the pre-made version,
and our model body is a more standard body,
so when I wear this suit,
I don't feel much difference.
Well,
the part we have more of is to move the point,
change it a little bit more.
Well,
for example,
like the night,
or say,
hey,
look,
our board.
Here,
do you see this curve?
Ah,
it's sticking out here,
here,
and here,
right?
Why is it sticking out here?
Well,
I won't wait for you to answer this question.
The reason it sticks out here is because
our board and the bottom board are sewn together,
but this corner is a pointy corner,
and this corner is a straight corner.
This corner is a pointy corner,
This corner is a straight corner, and when they are joined together, it is not a flat corner, and the line next to it is not a flat corner.
This is why we sometimes encounter some corners in the process of sewing, and we think that this length is correct.
Why is it protruding? It is because these two points are joined together, and the side is not a straight line.
Then how do we align it? We just put it together.
After that, we use the editing board tool to see if the length of one of them is not right.
Then we first match the length of it, and then simulate it.
After the simulation, we rotate the board and pin it up.
After pinning it up, you can see that the curve is not connected.
We use the editing board tool to select these two points and move them inward to make them a flat corner.
After it becomes a flat corner, it is normal now.
Thank you for watching.
See, it is more smooth.
So you have to be careful when you are doing it right.
Pin this line up to see if there is any problem.
Then here, we use wool fabric for this suit.
It is a thicker fabric.
The thickness I am talking about is that it looks a little thick.
Is there any solution to the calculation?
There is no solution to the calculation.
I don't understand what you are talking about.
Is it cardan or something?
Next, I will show you how to change the size of the model and the size of the basic model of the board.
First, we change the model to a fat model.
We only change the curved part first.
For example, the curved part is fat.
Then we reset the 3D arrangement position.
Reset it again.
Because we just changed the size of this model.
But the board is in its original position.
If we don't reset the 3D arrangement position again,
the board and the model will have a gap in the curved part.
It will be unstable.
So we reset the 3D arrangement position.
Set the board again.
Then open the simulation.
At this time, the size of this board and the virtual model are different.
The size of the board and the virtual model are not the same.
So we reset the 3D arrangement position.
Look, the 3D arrangement position is broken.
So we reset the 3D arrangement position first.
In the middle, we use the internal line as the seam allowance.
Then we create the seam allowance.
So we reset the middle seam allowance first.
Because the perimeter is stillniket odds for the 4D model.
Then I imagined,
In our model, theähr
is not as wide as this.
So I unexpected it narrow
Of course this is reasonable,
but you can make it with basic posture.
After 쉽ly make the perimeter atop a better size,
Let's see how to change it.
First of all, we don't care about the collar here.
Yes, we don't care about the collar here.
Let's first look at the position where it needs to be widened.
Here we are on the side.
Because this line in the middle is right on the length,
in order to make it easier to modify,
I will merge it directly in the middle.
After merging,
let's choose the side of the front first.
Add enough side volume to it first.
OK.
Let's first determine the curve of its waist here,
so that it is a relatively loose look.
Then we will make the following adjustments.
You will see how to mix sleeves and clothes later.
OK.
Then let's assume that its belly is also big.
It doesn't matter.
You just need to make it wider on the side.
Just make the whole side wider.
Then here is the bottom of the page.
You can see that
there is no bottom of the page.
When making clothes,
be careful.
Be careful.
When there is this kind of
bottom of the page,
as long as there is this kind of bottom of the page,
as long as you sew the sleeves,
the sleeves will not look good.
It just won't look good.
Because the bottom of the page
is relatively tight.
It doesn't have enough loose volume.
In this case,
you can do a hand squeeze action,
or you can do some
large-scale hand movements.
It doesn't look good.
Its wrinkles don't look good.
So we have to choose all the points
that form the bottom of the page.
This point,
and this one in the middle,
and this point next to it,
pull them down a little bit.
We have to give it enough volume.
We have to give it enough space to move.
Then it will look good.
This is the wrinkle.
Is this the width of the arm?
Well,
try to be
a little bit longer than the width of the arm.
But you don't have to
be the same as the width of the arm.
Because,
because you can
change the effect of the 3D space
little by little.
Look.
For example,
we are still tight here.
Look.
Look here.
Does this point
also have no amount of movement?
When it is exaggerated,
you can look at some ShiftX.
If you have Google,
you can look around this arm.
Look at whether it will be stuck here
in the process of its movement.
If it is stuck,
it will be a little tight.
But on the other hand,
if you just want to show that
this dress is not suitable for this person,
very tight,
then you don't have to change it.
You just let this night blind look like this.
OK.
In addition,
let's take a look at this picture again.
Why do I add a point here?
Because the curve above it
is actually fine.
That is,
it does not have a very obvious
stretching problem.
But it is stuck here in the night.
Do you have a feeling?
It feels like this night
is here.
Why is it here?
Look at this.
Is it very tight?
In fact,
your night should be like this.
Then turn around
and turn to this position.
It's almost OK.
But it's stuck here now.
So let's make a break here.
Then add this part separately.
See?
It has enough amount like this.
OK.
This is what you usually do
for some muscular men
or some people
or some models
that are larger in size.
Some points you need to change.
The night is especially important here.
Don't make it too tight.
Then choose the weight here.
Let's pull it down a little bit.
You'd better choose the angle
to see if there is this kind of
curve that is more powerful
or more obvious to block.
The back panel is too long.
Add a rope.
The panel is too long.
It has nothing to do with the rope.
The rope on the back panel
is usually only added with a number.
Not very similar.
Wait a minute.
I'll explain it to you.
Let's see how it works.
Wait a minute.
There is something behind.
OK.
Here we activate the sewing line.
Let it sew up here in the front.
OK.
After activating the sewing line,
see?
When we sew up here in the front,
the angle of the night is almost the same.
Then how much do you want to change?
You change it to the way I drew it.
See?
It's a little bit away
from where you really move.
So your sleeve
can be a suitable
and movable position.
And it can give you a nice fold.
Understand?
Kou Yi.
Then the waist here.
If it's the kind of thin waist.
It's the kind of muscle that's more developed.
It's very obvious.
If it's a triangle,
you can change the waist here a little bit.
But
look.
Our waist here.
If you change it too thin here,
but it's flat here,
it will have this kind of oblique fold.
Because your side curve
is not right.
OK.
And this curve on your side,
no matter how you change it,
don't let it
turn into a curve first,
and then protrude.
That is, its curve will always
only have a place to bend in.
Generally, it won't bend and protrude.
It won't look like a giant finger.
OK.
Then it's the neck here.
When a lot of people are making that dress,
they don't pay attention to
the position of the shoulder and neck.
It will look like this.
The clothes are tighter.
Of course, it's still that sentence.
If you want to make it look tight,
it's very good.
Then you don't want to change it.
But my habit is that I will put it
on this shoulder line.
Leave it in a sufficient position.
It's a little bit out of the way.
Because the suit is a relatively wide version.
It's like that.
A tight knit sweater.
That kind of.
For example.
In American movies,
there are often tight clothes.
The man in the white shirt
is not the same as that.
The suit itself is still quite wide.
So its shoulder line will still be longer.
Understand?
Because we are actually making suits now.
Then, including the front and middle here,
you can give it some more volume.
Then in the middle,
the sewing line is the position
where we are going to move the button.
Give it the volume to move out.
Then it's your collar here.
The collar here.
Because we will have a
turning collar structure later.
You must give it enough
this loose volume.
So move the collar out a little bit.
How to adjust the shoulder line to the outside.
You just pull this point out a little bit.
Just make up for the amount of the shoulder line.
Understand?
This is with everyone.
I have provided a lot of points.
That is, where do you want to change?
You just change that point.
Try not to change a line.
Changing a line is unless you are already sure.
This line has to be changed all the way.
Where does the board start to enter?
First of all,
you go to see a systematic board knowledge book.
You must not understand it.
There is no need to waste time.
You just have to remember
where there is less,
where there is more,
where there is a point,
that's it.
Understand?
Don't go to
very
There is a lot of research.
If you don't understand that structure,
you don't understand how to sew that sewing line.
You can come to the group to ask me.
But if you want to study books,
you can buy a book on clothing.
You can also buy the book on the board paper.
Including this back piece of it.
Let's make it a little wider.
In fact, it's almost the same as it is now.
The board shape is OK.
Oh,
it feels like a armor.
If that's the case,
there is no wrinkle.
There is our group number on the bottom left.
Group number and answer password.
If you want that suit,
there is no wrinkle.
That's easier.
That is,
you,
you have to
know how to avoid this kind of board shape problem.
Because,
to be honest,
there is no,
well,
there is no bottom.
You will keep adjusting,
keep adjusting.
Sometimes you may feel that after adjusting the board,
it's still very strange.
At this time,
we will change our mind.
Anyway,
it's a suit.
There are a lot of suits.
There is no wrinkle.
You can just increase the bending force.
Because the bending force is increased,
it also has no wrinkle.
Right?
Yeah.
Sometimes you change the board shape.
If you don't,
like me,
a little bit of glue,
a little bit of blood,
you change the board shape.
It's a big problem to change it yourself.
Okay,
let's go back to this thin model.
first of all,
let's see if there is any problem with this bottom.
Can you imagine if our arm will touch this line during the rotation?
Will it?
I can't wait.
It will.
Just imagine,
this arm,
during the rotation,
it will still be stuck to this line.
Because it is connected here,
connected to the position of the chest muscle,
but it will still touch it.
So,
so this one,
so this bottom line,
we actually have to go down a little bit.
Do you understand?
Look,
if you look at it now,
it won't affect it.
Including this,
this point is the same.
Let's go down a little bit,
so that it doesn't affect it.
Okay,
then let's look at this model again.
now this model,
you see,
why do I move this point back here?
You see,
our front here is actually very flat,
very good.
The main problem is in the back here.
First of all,
when you move this board back,
it's here.
We are equivalent to a,
we are equivalent to a small triangle area.
After that,
it can be more smoothly poked here.
Otherwise,
if this point is on the inside,
no matter how you move it,
is it that this amount is not enough?
But if you can't be sure
whether to move this point out,
or this,
that is, you can't be sure
whether this point is out,
or this point is out,
you can try both points.
You try them all,
see which one works better,
which one works better,
choose which one.
Because your side,
it,
is not enough,
the problem is not that this point is out,
it is this point.
You can try to pull the point wide.
Wait a moment,
let me pour some water.
Okay, let's continue.
Then look at this,
this is the back structure.
Is there another one here?
It doesn't stick,
it doesn't stick to this part of the human body curve,
right?
After that,
we are going to start repairing this part.
First of all,
you move the line down,
that is,
you want to see,
move this point down,
is it actually equivalent to
digging a triangle?
Right?
In fact,
if we dig a triangle,
it can already be repaired like this,
because it is actually
a triangle,
so this one will appear.
There is only one
fold here.
Okay,
in addition,
there is another way.
Then we use a fake seam,
and then pinch these two points.
After pinching it,
this curve
is actually already attached.
Can you understand?
This is also what we said before,
in the video of
adding a line,
in the video of adding a line,
we said that
if you don't know
how to dig a triangle,
you go to this place,
add two fake seams,
pinch it,
after pinching it,
yes,
is it equivalent to
we put the middle,
these two points
of the just-seamed,
and put together,
this part?
This part will be removed a little,
so we go from
the point of the collar
to the just-seamed needle here,
it is actually to add a stitch,
but the back,
because your back is wider,
it is not the same as the chest,
胸部的绳是因为胸是凸出来的,它有一个起伏,所以它的绳道,就是它的绳道会开到你的胸点为止,但是你的背是一个宽阔的平面,所以你这个绳一开就得开到领子这里,也就是说我会直接画一根线,刚我们的甲纹针是不是点了这里点了这里,那我就从这个点往这里拉一条线,然后从这个点往这里拉一条线,
然后我们再挖掉中间的那一部分之后缝起来,看到没有,它现在就是平了,看到了没有,学会了没有,家人们,快记笔记,学会了没有,学会空义啊,对,对,就是这样,所以现在我们这个背部的曲线就拉的比较漂亮了,啊,懂了吧,嗯。
啊,我平时为了就是找出这种大家可以听得懂的方法,真是绞尽脑汁,然后我们再把腋下这里往下拉一点就可以了,啊,当然过程你肯定是要一点一点调的,啊,最后我们把这里合并了就可以,好,合并完了之后,这个背部有一些曲线,就是比如说有这种凹陷的点,你也可以用类似的方法去解决,
但是背部的话呢,因为我们最后里面会垫的一些衣服可以撑起来,问题倒不是很大,然后我们再加袖子,啊,袖子的话我们可以直接到这个Modular Configurator,就是模块化控制器当中,啊,找到,嗯,西装,然后找到袖子,好,找到袖子之后,我们删除这个弹袖条,就这一小个版片我们不用,我们只要这两个完整的袖子,
部分就可以了,然后另外一边删掉,因为我们要创建对称版片嘛,啊,这个我之前有提到过,我们软件内部的这个,啊,模块化它目前没有左右对称,所以我们先留一边,好,先留,先留完一边之后我们等一下可以对称过去,好,现在我们有了这个袖子,对不对,但是袖子如果你现在直接把这个袖子缝到西装上面,
肯定是不对的,它会有不对称,就是,它的,你看它的曲线本身就对不上,看到没有,我们页下刚刚是做的比较,嗯,就是,做的比较贴身的,但是这个袖子它是不贴身的,好,那这个时候有两种方法,啊,第一个方法呢,就是,改袖子,但是其实袖子改才比较麻烦,所以有的时候我们认知上觉得,哎,我们也不知道,
页下已经改的够了,但是实际上你的页下其实它不一定够,就是我们以为,啊,它这样贴身很漂亮,但是实际上它有可能还是会有一点影响到,所以呢,我们就给这个袖子的版片,呃,加一点透明度,有的有的,MD10里面有的,从那个很古老的版本当中就已经有Modular Configurator,就是模块化控制器这个功能,
平时不知道而已,里面其实有很多现成的衣服的,如果你打开Modular Configurator里面,你没有找到这个模块的话呢,左上角有一个下载,下载一下就可以了,但是一般情况下是肯定有的,啊,好,那接下来我们转到侧面的视角,现在我们,呃,这个袖子是有透明的,嗯,透明的,就是设置了透明度嘛,对吧,
那我们就可以从侧面视角去依照这个透明度,来改这个西装的袖笼,嗯,啊,有录播的哈,有录播的,啊,对的对的对的,其实自己打版的话呢,是有一些辛苦的,你直接从网上去找现成的版子都比较方便,你可以去百度上面,上面搜,比如说你要做西装,就是西装纸样,
如果你是在Pinterest上面搜的话,你就搜,blah blah blah blah,加pattern,比如说是T-shirt pattern,或者是,嗯,skirt pattern,它都可以搜出来,pattern是p-a-t-t-e-r-n,啊,好,那这里我为什么画了一个内部线啊,是因为,我们看一下这个袖子的构造,
袖子它是分大袖和小袖,为什么会有大袖和小袖呢,小袖就是你的手肘靠外的这一部分,有一根分割线,啊,这个,然后,前面就是这个大片的,对,pattern,然后,嗯,后面就是那一小片,啊,所以你的袖子是有一个大片缝一个小片嘛,对吧,那中间它有一根线,对不对,
嗯,
那我们现在要做的事情,
就是在你按侧面视角,啊,就是四或者六的视角下面,因为中间它有一根分割线会藏在叶下嘛,啊,我们看一下最终的那个参考图,啊,不知道大家能不能看,好,这根线是,哎,这里会有,这里会有一根线藏在叶下,看到没有,这根线,所以我们要做的事情是在这个,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深的,嗯,大深
版片上面找到那个和这个叶下的线对应的这个点,懂吗?所以我们在侧边视角的时候,你去画一个内部线,啊,参考一下这个点,找到这个点的位置,然后我们再去讲后面怎么改。
好,找到这个内部线之后呢,选择这个点,右键选择对齐,然后增加点到版片外线上,好,增加完点之后,这个点就是我们等一下用来做标记的点了,然后我们现在先整体拉宽这个绣笼,让它尽量和你的袖子的横截面是对得上的,我说的尽量就是尽量对得上,就是尽量再对得上。
在侧边的情况下,在正的侧边的视角下面,它的绣笼底部是对得上的,看到没有?
好,在这样对得上的情况之后呢,啊,我们中间的那个标记的点,以这个点为分界线,开始从袖子最高的点缝版片的前侧和后侧。
首先你前侧这里是一整根线嘛,所以我们用自由缝纹按住shift键进行一对多的缝。
就可以了,缝到那个对,对齐袖子侧边的点为止。
然后我们再换n比n自由缝纹,先选这一侧的点,然后按enter键,然后从这个点开始,点击点击点击点击,再按enter键,结束。
好,现在我们缝纹线是不是就创建好了,然后我们就缝好了。
但是呢,这里我,是,这里我出现了一个问题。
就是我忘记了我模特的手臂是张开的。
好,所以在这里我们重新安排一下版片。
好,你可以选择重设2D安排位置。
因为当你选择重设2D安排位置之后,你可以同时选中这两个版片,把它们安排在虚拟模特的手部侧边,就可以了。
好,现在呢,我们的这个绣笼线其实基本上已经是对上了的。
好,左边这里我们用完了modular configuration。
这个modular configuration的话,可以先回归到library,就是这个图库窗口。
之后呢,我们再找到这个虚拟模特的姿势更换一下。
如果你用的是自己的模型的话,那你最好是准备一个比较T的T pose,和,哦,就是没那么T的T pose,和一个比较A的A pose。
好,缝完之后我们再给它换一个版。
is to change the fabric. After changing the fabric, let's take a look here.
Compare the version of our original state.
Does this sleeve now pull your collar out?
Right, this is the original state.
It's ok, it's very flat, it looks very comfortable.
But now let's look at this side.
Is the sleeve pulling your clothes?
Right?
Okay, close the mouth at night, how do you adjust your body to get close to it?
First, close the mouth at night, not close to the body.
Is it because the point of closing the mouth at night is long that it is not close to the body?
It is either high or long.
If it is high, it will have a corner to roll over.
Let me see if I can draw that.
Oh, I can't draw it.
If it is high, it will be like this.
If it is high, it will poke up first, right?
Then the long part will roll over.
This is high.
But if it is high, it will poke up first, right?
Then the long part will roll over. This is high.
If it's long, it will just have a certain amount here, it won't poke up first.
So you need to either keep this point in, or pull the point down.
You check what's going on.
If you can't tell destiny and pattern, you check what's going on.
And this adjustment is done when you're anti-activating your sleeve.
Do you understand that?
Because sometimes, you can sew at the summer heat,
or some A pose, your hands won't open up very much.
Right, get close to your body before adding sleeves.
If you add sleeves, you will be pulled apart.
That means your sleeves have some problems.
Let's take a look, because I will tell you next.
This suit has this problem.
Look, let's look at this suit now.
This side is all OK, it's all beautiful.
It's normal when it doesn't add sleeves.
But is it wrong to add sleeves here?
Let's look at the problem first.
First of all, is the collar pulled out?
Right, look, the collar is so long.
Your sleeves will end at this point.
The collar is pulled from here, it will be pulled over.
So is it that the shoulder is missing here?
Can you understand?
If you add this shoulder line a little longer,
will it be pulled over?
So let's make the shoulder line a little longer.
OK.
This is what I said.
When you usually do it,
if you feel that something is missing,
just fill it up a little bit.
OK.
Let's give the shoulder line enough volume.
After that, we are going to start to adjust the sleeve line.
Because we did the base of this board before.
These sizes are all on one picture,
one reference paper pattern.
But this sleeve was added in later.
So you can't make sure that the curve of this sleeve
and this suit you made must be right.
So we are going to start to change the curve of this sleeve
so that it is right with your suit.
Do you understand?
Then here we take a look first.
First of all, let's choose these two lines in the front.
Then in the attribute editor,
you can see their length.
The total length of the two of them is 290 mm,
which is 29 cm.
But now,
the length of this sleeve is only less than 277 mm.
Right?
So let's make this sleeve longer and wider first.
Here we are going to make it wider first.
Because you see this sleeve,
you can actually feel that this sleeve is a little tight.
Right?
Because there is a crevice here,
but there is no sleeve on the sleeve.
That means the long sleeve here is short.
So let's drag the sleeve along the horizontal direction.
So that the length of the sleeve is longer.
Then you will definitely say,
hey, it's the same length of the sleeve.
Why can't we pull this point up?
It can also be lengthened, right?
But if you pull this point up,
then the sleeve will be higher, right?
Because this point doesn't move.
If you don't move this point,
if you pull this point long,
will it poke out like this?
So let's try not to touch this sleeve.
Let's pull it wider in the horizontal direction first.
Okay, let's pull it wider to 290.
After that, let's start the simulation.
Hey, is it loose now?
Right?
Look at our front here.
Does it look loose when you look at it from the front?
The size gives you the feeling
that it is not as serious as it was before.
Right?
But we will still optimize this sleeve a little bit later.
Okay, let's look at the back after we finish the front.
And then here,
when I just looked at the front,
it has some wide sleeves.
So let's put this point inside a little bit,
and then lift the sleeve up a little bit,
to evenly distribute the added amount.
Okay, add a little bit to it,
and then simulate it.
See?
Okay.
Because this place was wide just now,
let's take a look at the comparison effect.
Just now, I only pulled it wide horizontally here.
This point here is wide horizontally,
which leads to this line becoming longer.
The price is whether there is a lot of volume here.
So I choose to put this point back a little bit,
and lift this point up a little bit.
In this way, its curve is like this.
Its horizontal arm is not that wide.
Can you understand?
Because your arm has a dimension.
This arm has a dimension.
This arm has a dimension from this point
to the other point of the sleeve that has not been displayed yet.
This wide is the dimension of your arm's circle.
Why does this circle look loose and scattered now?
It's because you're too wide.
So let's move this point inside.
So it's a little bit narrower here.
And then lift this sleeve up a little bit.
In this way, we can also make up for the length of the sleeve.
But the length of the sleeve is not particularly high.
Can you understand?
If you can't understand,
you can give me a comment now.
I can explain it to you again.
In other words,
because the sleeve is too wide and too fat now,
we will shorten the sleeve in this direction.
We will move this amount to the number direction.
Okay.
Then let's take a look at the effect after we change it.
Here I found that it is wide.
So we narrow it down a little bit in the level direction.
And then make up for it in the number direction.
After making up for it,
you can see that this shape is very beautiful here.
Right?
The shape in front of us is OK.
In fact, at this time,
we almost know how to adjust it.
The same goes for the back piece.
If the back piece needs to be widened,
let's first measure how much the total length of your back piece is,
and then widen it according to this total length.
Here I found that my back piece should be a little longer,
so I moved it separately.
Slightly modify its length,
so that the total length of the two of them is the same as the sleeve of the back piece.
Okay.
After we are almost done here,
we select this sleeve back piece,
press Ctrl D,
and create a symmetrical back piece.
Okay.
Now our sleeve part is almost done.
Here you will see that it still has some strange pattern problems.
Right?
There will be some problems here that do not seem to be very close.
We will continue to teach you how to fix this later.
So everyone is watching us.
So when you are watching our live stream,
as well as teaching videos,
you can rest assured that
I will try my best to teach you how to fix the problems I see.
First, let's look at the back piece of this sleeve.
The front piece here is very standard.
This curve is very beautiful.
Right?
What we are going to do at this time is to anti-activate the seam allowance.
Anti-activate the seam allowance here.
After anti-activation, we can see the problem.
Because you can't see the problem at night.
In fact, the problem at night is not very big.
The problem is at the point where our sleeve is.
There is a lot of fabric just now, right?
After we anti-activate the fabric,
look at this sleeve.
Have you found a problem?
When the sleeve is anti-activated,
it is high.
Because our whole sleeve still has a seam allowance.
We did not anti-activate the seam allowance at the bottom.
We only anti-activated the seam allowance of these two threads.
Right?
After anti-activation, you can see that this point is protruding.
We just pull this point down.
Okay, don't worry.
Let's pull this point down first.
After pulling it down,
look at the curve on its side.
Is it right?
Try to make it right.
Because when we just turned to the back piece,
did you see that the bottom is connected?
We only anti-activate the part that will be affected.
Then we anti-activate these two threads again.
Take a look.
Okay.
Is this problem reduced now?
Right?
After that,
we have to use these anti-activation methods repeatedly
to make up for these problems.
Right.
The seam allowance can be anti-activated separately.
Okay.
Because we pulled the sleeve down just now,
the sleeve is down.
Is this thread short?
We are going to start to fill the line.
We just pull this point out a little bit.
Let it fill this amount out.
So I said,
this is the most troublesome part of changing clothes,
especially changing sleeves.
But everyone must remember the logic we changed.
First of all,
we first put this sleeve itself,
that is, the large sleeve,
we make it suitable.
Then we make the sleeve match the sleeve a little bit.
Understand?
Okay.
Then let's look at this curve.
Let's take a look here.
What's wrong with your curve?
When we do the back,
is this line usually straight?
Right?
The line of this sleeve will be straight.
But what's wrong with it here?
This is the shoulder line.
Then it's here.
Because it may not be clear in the video now.
This curve is turned over first.
Then there is a turning point in the middle.
It turns again.
So there must be some problems with this curve.
Okay.
Is this the point of the curve?
You see,
when I choose this,
you can see it very clearly here.
In fact,
when we usually wear a suit,
this point should be like this.
Then pull a line straight down.
It's more beautiful.
But it has this extra piece now.
So we use the curve to pull this extra piece back.
Okay.
Then simulate it again.
After the simulation,
you will find that
why do I put this piece,
this piece is clearly changed a little bit.
But there is still a curve here.
There are some MD10s
that have the anti-fog of the feng shui line.
The anti-fog of the feng shui line
is also a function of a long time ago.
Okay.
Then we will
fill in the curve here.
Okay.
In addition to filling it out,
I also changed the curve here a little bit.
Because you are back,
this line is straight.
So our curve is also straight.
And then here below,
give it a little bit of curve.
Here,
you can just simply remember
that the curve of your back piece
is generally straight above.
Then give it a little bit of curve below.
It's not a whole curve.
Say it again.
It's straight above.
Give it a little bit of curve below.
Okay.
After we finished the modification,
it still has a little bit of this
small problem between the feng shui line and the feng shui line.
Okay.
Then we can continue to change it later.
In fact,
the most difficult thing to do when making a suit
is to change the sleeves here,
especially the back piece here.
In fact,
it's like this.
If you don't mind,
you can also go outside
or you can just use this
moving tool to move it.
It's just that
I hope everyone
when watching our live broadcast,
you can learn
how to know
where to change
and where not to change.
Understand?
Because there is still a little bit of that problem behind us now.
Then if you are tired,
you can do it like me first.
I usually do it more tired.
I think this point
I hope to think about it later.
I'll sew up the collar first.
Then give it a little folding angle,
which is to give it a little
folding angle of this feng shui line,
let it turn over.
Because you imagine
our version is a straight-forward shape,
it's not a straight-forward shape.
The version is a straight-forward shape.
Then we have to let this collar turn over.
Is it a straight-forward shape?
When the middle of this feng shui line goes in,
yes,
I also think it's very real.
It's just that I'm usually really tired.
I'll do some other accessories first,
change the taste,
change the mood,
and then print the version.
Here,
ask everyone again.
Hello, hello,
good evening.
Then we print the whole version.
You can see that
when we print this version,
it's very small.
And now our version is very beautiful,
isn't it?
This is due to our
better adjustment of the version.
These operating habits
of your line
are pulled straighter and more beautiful.
The turning tool can also be used.
Why don't I use the turning tool here?
Because
this point is to be mentioned to everyone.
What you are doing now is a straight line.
What you are doing now is a suit.
And I've made the collar independent.
The turning tool now
is in the 11 of Marvelous Design.
It will have a symmetrical connection on the left and right.
Of course, you can turn off this connection.
It's just that I turn on the connection.
Then,
is it now that the two panels are stacked together?
Right?
If I use the folding tool directly
to fold these two panels,
then is it,
for example,
when I turn this panel,
because it is a curved panel,
the other panel,
is it possible?
I'm just saying it's possible.
It will interfere with you.
If it interferes,
it may not be stable.
Right?
So,
my general habit
may be that I will give it a
Of course,
if it is,
for example,
like a pants,
it will not cause the upper and lower
to interfere because of the turning.
Then,
I will use this folding arrangement tool,
which is the turning tool you said.
But now,
the fact is that this collar
may be inserted into the panel
because it is left and right symmetrical.
Because this panel
and this panel are still stacked together.
Maybe this panel,
for example,
when this panel is worn,
it may be worn to this panel,
it will still be inside,
or it will be touched.
So,
I set the folding angle directly here.
Then,
use the hardening panel
to let them turn themselves over directly.
Because after hardening the panel,
its folding
can be applied quickly.
So,
I will use it.
Well,
there is no live broadcast of the Tencent class.
My live broadcasts are all on Bilibili.
I only have the live broadcast of the Tencent class.
Well,
if you buy the paid course,
there will be.
But,
because today is an official live broadcast,
of course,
that is also official.
Today is a general,
a large-scale live broadcast.
Well,
today I will do it on Bilibili.
So,
you can pay attention to our Bilibili.
Well,
if you pay attention to our Bilibili,
you can see that
the Bilibili has been folded.
Well,
now,
I would like to ask you again.
First of all,
my Bilibili,
because I am looking at the surface of the濃密紋理,
so,
you don't know
if my Bilibili is facing the front or the back,
right?
Well,
I want to ask,
suppose my Bilibili is facing the back,
and my clothes are facing the front,
right?
Because my Bilibili is turned over,
Well,
my Bilibili is turned over,
right?
So,
how much is the folding angle of the濃密紋理 in the middle?
Can you answer it?
How much is the folding angle of my Bilibili now?
It is turned over now.
Are you still there?
Do you know the length of this collar?
Yes.
Oh,
it's not right.
I see some people say it's 0,
some people say it's 180,
and some people say it's over 90.
First of all,
oh,
I finally see a correct one.
Ah,
it's 360 degrees.
Here we are again,
again,
720,
who said that?
The highest is only 360.
Because this Bilibili is facing the front,
facing the front of this Bilibili,
so,
the folding angle of the濃密紋理
is facing the front,
right?
So,
the folding angle of the濃密紋理
is facing the front,
right?
So,
the folding angle of the濃密紋理
is facing the front,
right?
So,
the folding angle of the濃密紋理
is facing the front,
right?
Then,
is the folding line in the middle
is it a folding line to the inside?
Okay,
let's take a look again,
I've already thought that
this collar
must be
too small
for my friends
to be tell.
Okay,
let's take another look.
These are two Bilibili,
Let's let's simulate that.
Let's simulate that.
These are two Bilibili.
Okay,
let's simulate that.
okay,
Okay, your collar is turned over like this, right?
Your collar is, is, your collar is, no, it's torn, your collar is, oh, we, oh, okay, let's assume your collar is turned over like this, right?
Your collar, oh, it's turned over like this.
Think about it, when they are facing the outside, this thread is facing the inside.
So the fold angle of the collar is more than 180 degrees, that is, 360 degrees, do you understand?
Then if I want this line to be facing the outside,
if I want this line to be facing the outside, then the fold angle of this line should be,
if I want this line to be facing the outside, then the fold angle of this line should be more than 180 degrees, that is, 360 degrees, do you understand?
Huh?
That's right, that's right, it's zero, I just wanted to scare you.
That's right, that's right, it's zero.
If it's facing the outside, it should be zero.
Not 90, 180 is the line, 90 is the angle, 90 is an angle, do you understand?
Take a look at this sheet of paper, this is zero.
Let's take a look again, this is zero, this is 90, 90 is an angle, 180 is an angle, angle.
270 is an angle facing the inside.
360 is completely inward, see?
360 is completely inward.
If I put these two fixed needles a little closer, they are completely inward.
If it is 270, it is...
Let's ask again, what is 270?
What is 270?
When the angle of my Frenzy line is 270, it is...
Yes, it is actually an opening point,
that is, this foot is inward,
that is, it is facing inward, and then it is 90.
You can also understand it as 90 outward,
which is 90 outward from the back.
OK.
So you have to figure out,
is it 180, which is facing outward,
or is it facing inward?
OK, let's continue.
Where are we?
You have to know that
today's live broadcast may be at 11 o'clock.
Then we will put the collar on.
After putting the collar on,
we will use the free sewing tool to sew it here.
After sewing,
here is also using the free sewing tool to find its corresponding position.
Press the Shift key to do multiple sewing.
Put the collar,
that is, the front collar,
that is,
you can't say the front collar,
that is, the part of the folded collar is pinned up.
After it is pinned up,
arrange the board.
Did you see that when I arranged this collar,
it was inserted diagonally like this, right?
OK,
this question is because
our current collar,
it was bent in the 2D window before.
Did you see it?
It is bent.
So when you arrange it on the arrangement point,
it is bent.
Understand?
So before we arrange it,
you need to put it in the 2D window
as flat as possible.
When it is flat,
then rearrange it,
rearrange this board,
it is flat.
This is why sometimes
when you change the board,
you will find that when I arrange it on the arrangement point,
why is it bent?
And then because of the collar here,
we have folded it before,
so we freeze the collar
so that the other one
can be sewn faster
with the collar next to it.
OK,
here,
we draw an internal line.
Use a multidirectional,
an internal multidirectional line tool
to draw a line.
The point of this line
is the point we just folded
and the point next to it.
It is not drawn directly from this bottom point,
it is drawn from a position in the middle.
After drawing,
print this board.
OK,
so now,
if I want to fold this plate,
what is the angle of fold that I am going to give now?
Yes, that's right,
360.
I saw that many friends
have already answered it,
it is 360.
Let us print the plates
so that you can apply the angle of fold faster.
Then,
Then we can activate these four scales at the same time
and then let them simulate it together.
Okay, now that we've simulated it,
our scales are done here.
That's how it is.
Like this one in my video,
it's called flat scale scale.
The flat scale scale looks like this.
There is a small gap in the middle of this sandpaper scale here.
It looks even.
We will learn together
how to make other scales.
First, we can...
Well we have the break points in between of these scales.
Let's make the middle bit longer.
Then additional line at the two sides of the scale.
One more saying rule,
This is called the chisel.
The chisel will have a protruding point here.
So we move this point up in the middle.
Because there is a break point in the middle,
this break point is connected to the top.
So we move this point up directly here,
and it will become the chisel.
This point is sharp.
Then we sew up the corresponding position.
After sewing up, we start the simulation.
This is called the chisel.
Can you see it?
So it is very important for us to divide the chisel.
Because the chisel is divided into sections,
we can quickly transform the chisel.
Of course, you can also adjust the shape of the chisel according to your needs.
It's just that in general,
the suit will match the flat chisel,
which is what it looks like now,
and the chisel.
Just now,
there was a chisel with a sharp protrusion.
The chisel usually matches the chisel of Yan Wei.
Then let's take a look at another type of chisel,
which is called the green chisel.
The name of the green chisel is called the green chisel.
So it looks round,
like a fruit.
Let's measure the internal line first.
Let's measure their total length first.
Take a look.
Here we can see the length of its 2D line.
You can see the center of isso,
the length,
a flat chisel front and
two flat chisel.
Opposite,
you can see the center of its large square.
What about here?
If you are making a green fruit, you need to cut off this piece of paper.
You can see here that I deleted it at the end.
I think it's a bit of an impact.
If you delete it, you need to re-sew the piece of paper.
After sewing, remember to try it from a folding angle.
It may look a bit strange here.
I don't know what kind of collar I made.
This is just an analogy with you.
If you look at the M&E of Zhou Jialun's greatest work,
there is a set of Zhou Jialun and Lang Lang fighting.
Then he wore a suit of blue birdcage, right?
There is a vest in it.
The vest is made of blue birdcage.
It's the kind of vest I'm wearing right now.
Let's use a rectangle as a substitute first.
Then we can make a round corner with a round-shaped curve here.
After making a round corner, press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical plate.
So in fact, blue birdcage is often used on the vest.
Especially when making some more formal clothes,
the traditional suit will be placed on top of the vest.
Of course, some women's suit jackets will also be paired with blue birdcage.
The blue birdcage is like this step by step.
Make a rectangle first.
Then we can widen the back center a little bit.
Because when we folded it just now,
the amount of the back center was too small.
Then this collar looks wrinkled.
This is because our blue birdcage is not the same as the other two collars.
The other two collars are two collars pinned together.
The blue birdcage is a separate plate.
So when you make the blue birdcage,
you have to make this plate a little wider.
Understand?
Of course, you don't need to remember this.
Just remember it very clearly.
You just have to follow the effect of the 3D window.
You have to tell yourself to react quickly.
Oh, it may be that the collar is short.
That's why there is such a problem.
We'll add some more collars to it.
Understand?
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Anyway, when everyone is doing whatever effect,
try to make sure that the 3D window is the effect you want.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Okay, then let's make a sleeve.
Here is the sleeve of the suit.
Okay.
We're going to make a fork for it.
Open fork.
Okay.
How do you do this open fork?
First of all,
we're going to focus on the line on the side.
Then we choose the inner line of the body.
Oh, no.
Choose the panel line expansion.
Then remember to select the inner line of the body.
Okay.
Then after the panel line expansion.
Here, the number of expansion options is 1.
If it's tight,
choose the width of this fork.
Then here we delete the excess inner line.
Because there is actually an open fork on the side of the sleeve.
We call it open fork.
That is, there is an extra rectangular panel.
Then this rectangular panel
will be covered by another sleeve.
Understand?
So we have this button on the side.
And it can have the amount of activity.
Okay.
Then we choose to convert this to a button.
Because in fact,
the button is added to this
multiple rectangular structure.
And when we adjust it,
we can adjust the angle of this button.
Okay.
Then we do this open fork position of the button.
Here we just match their angles.
Then put the button on.
Oh, back to the craft class.
I try to make it as simple as possible.
In short, we are going to do this next.
The structure of the sleeve movement.
Then we adjust the button type
that has been adjusted before when we made the vest.
Drag it to the button.
Okay.
So that the size of our button is OK.
Then the side.
There used to be a sewing line here.
We deleted the sewing line.
Because here we already have the button as a substitute.
After that,
now we can see
whether this embroidered panel is outside,
but the embroidered panel is inside.
So now we are going to use the selection grid tool.
Put this part,
which is the protruding grid,
into it.
So we choose here.
Select the grid.
The set of tools.
Select this part of the grid.
Then in the 2D space.
Oh, in the 3D space.
Push this grid in.
Okay.
Let me tell you again.
Select the grid.
The set of tools.
Then it's like,
um,
it's like using PS.
Here.
Select this part of the grid.
Okay.
After selecting,
we can see that this part of the grid in the 3D space is green.
Then we use the positioning tool to select this grid.
Push it in.
Okay.
After that,
the embroidered panel is stacked here.
After stacking,
we use the button button tool
to put the button button and the outer button button on it.
Now it's the embroidered panel we made.
Did you learn it?
So this is how the side panel is made.
This is how it's done.
Just select a part,
a small section of this panel line.
Then the panel line is expanded.
The part with more rectangle shapes is made.
Then put the button button on it.
Then use the selection grid tool.
If they overlap,
use the selection grid tool to handle the panel.
After handling it,
remember to put the button button on it at the end.
Don't put the button button on it at the beginning.
Okay.
There is a loop.
Then we go to the button button.
Then we go to the bottom of the button button.
Adjust its width.
That's right.
Today's live broadcast,
I also prepared a long time.
I also want to tell you a little bit more clearly.
So that when you do the suit in the future,
you can do it more easily.
Well,
we have now made a side button button, right?
Because the button button,
sometimes our panel is
left and right.
Some of our panels,
the left side is the button button,
the right side is the button button.
So in our software,
your button button and button button
will not be based on your symmetry relationship,
but is automatically symmetrical.
So here,
we have to select the button button and button button at the same time.
Then right-click to select the duplicate symmetry edit panel.
OK.
After copying,
we can see the other side.
The button button and button button here
are automatically symmetrical.
We can see that
in fact,
if you are directly on the button,
there will be some problems here.
Because we haven't dealt with the grid here yet,
right?
And we were here before.
The button button on the other side is not deleted.
You can see that here,
our panel is not
here.
The button button and button button here are on the button.
OK.
Then for convenience,
just for a while,
wait a minute,
don't have any problems.
We will use this selection grid tool first.
Put this grid in,
put it in,
put it in the right place.
And
there is one more thing to pay attention to here.
That is,
sometimes you may think that
I can just put it in and it's okay.
But I think
you try your best.
Anyway,
we have already used this
positioning tool to push it in.
Then we will use the rotation
to rotate it to the same angle as this side.
In this way,
it can prevent more
of that
the button button and the button eye
will have unstable problems.
OK.
You can see that
even if I have adjusted it in advance,
but because of the relationship between this and the button,
it still has an unstable place.
This button button still has this problem,
right?
If there is such a problem,
you don't have to worry about it.
You don't have to feel that your button button
may have to be adjusted again.
We can adjust it one by one.
First,
select the moving button button tool
and select it at the same time.
Or press the Shift key
and click on these buttons at the same time.
Select the right key,
reset,
arrange,
and arrange the position.
Look carefully.
Select all the buttons
and select reset 3D position.
After resetting the 3D position,
press the control key to simulate it.
It will automatically reset.
Then press the control key,
it will be arranged.
We don't need to pull the buttons out one by one.
Do you know?
Of course,
if it is a special situation,
you may need to adjust it manually.
But in most cases,
you reset the 3D arrangement position,
it will be arranged.
Do you understand?
Okay.
Hello.
Good evening, everyone.
Thank you for watching this late.
Okay.
Next,
let's take a look at the structure of the back.
Because of the structure of the back,
we actually have nothing to avoid.
We just did some collar,
and the sleeves.
Oh,
relax first.
Just do it.
Then we still have to deal with the back problem.
First of all,
when dealing with the back problem,
let's change the idea here.
Then we pull this,
because now we can't find the problem,
where does it appear,
right?
We also changed the sleeve,
also changed,
oh,
we also changed the sleeve,
also changed the sleeves.
Oh,
his back still has a strange place.
Then we will first turn on the back version.
Take a look.
Hey,
when we turn on the version,
you go to see his back,
these structural lines,
is it actually quite horizontal and vertical?
Right?
Okay,
well,
if that's the case,
then the problem must be in the back version.
He must have some problems.
In addition,
let's take a look at the line of the shoulder.
Because we are now against the back of the fire,
so,
um,
the back of these sewing lines will not be affected.
Is this shoulder line,
it was originally flat,
and suddenly a part came out here,
right?
Then do we say,
this is also naturally vertical in the sleeve,
is there a little more shoulder line here?
Right?
Of course,
this little bit,
it doesn't necessarily affect it,
but we can also optimize this part,
so we put this side point in a little bit,
and you look at the point in the front,
ah,
when we didn't change this shoulder line just now,
is it very sharp?
Okay,
let's take a look again,
let's go back and take a look again,
ah,
when we didn't change this point,
this corner,
is this edge very sharp?
Then it is paired with the back piece,
even though they can be shuffled into a straight line,
but for the sleeve of it.
Because the sleeve is a linear structure,
they are shuffled into a plane of three pieces,
so our most simple method
is to ensure that the corner is not so sharp,
and the bottom of the foot want to
meet
it too much and
here is the który
that is, in short,
There won't be any weird problems when you do it, you know, because we can't say that we can't force everyone to be very understanding, right?
This is not realistic, so as long as we remember that this kind of balance position is as straight as possible, it may be more convenient for us, and it is easier to operate.
So at the same time as we move this point inwards, we can see that its sharpness is gradually reduced.
When we move this point inwards, is it that the thread is not as protruding as it was just now?
So I want to repeat it with you again, that is, when you usually make your own board, you must make sure that there is no more than one,
and then you can properly counter-activate the board that matches him.
Or counter-activate the thread between them to see if they are OK in their natural state.
If there is already a problem with just these two boards, then you add the third board, which may cause more problems, right?
Okay, now we have the front and the sleeves in harmony, and the bottom of the page and the sleeves in harmony.
It looks good.
At this time, let's activate it.
Then you can see that there are actually a lot of problems in the back here.
If you open the simulation, first of all, it will affect the middle, right?
Then let's try it again.
If we cancel the back of the sewing line, that is, if we counter-activate them first, you can see that in fact,
when the back is not sewed together, the lines on the side here seem to be quite normal.
So the problem that happens in this version is because we have learned step by step that it is the problem of the back.
Then we have to study whether the back is the problem of the shoulder line, or the problem of the sleeve, or the problem of the back center, or the problem of the side.
In fact, you can come step by step.
You can counter-activate the shoulder line and then look at the others, right?
You can also counter-activate the sleeve and then look at the other positions, right?
It's just that we just chose the back center.
Then I found that when I counter-activated this back piece, it seemed to be quite normal.
Then the problem may be that the back is too tight here.
Do you understand?
Although it sounds very vague, it is indeed a way for us to solve the problem step by step.
Okay, first of all, let's fill in the line in the back center.
After filling it out, sew the back center here.
Okay, after sewing, let's take a look at the sleeve here.
See if there is any problem.
After putting them together, first of all, if we look from the back, the waist here on the side is tighter.
Then we put a little light on his waist.
After putting a little light on it, let's look at the back.
After putting a little light on it, let's switch to the side and see if his amount is OK.
After it is OK, we add a dot to the corresponding point on his waist.
Then put a little bit of his bottom plate in it.
The reason for this is actually easier to understand.
Let's take a look at this picture on the side.
When we switched to the side just now, it was obvious that there were two big folds here.
It was obvious that there were two big folds here.
The back here is OK, but there is a big fold here at the bottom.
There is a big fold here, right?
In fact, it means that there is a part of your waist here.
Do you understand?
That is, there is a lot of light on his waist here.
Then we will add two dots here on his waist and here in the back center.
Because the suit, his back here may add some, for example,
The difference is that we just sewed this structure here.
So it may have this structure.
So his back center may not be a whole plate.
And the probability is that it will not be a whole plate.
In this case, or we can merge the straight line above and the bottom line is separated.
In this case, we don't have to force it on the back of the suit.
We can also use the point at the bottom to narrow the waist.
And the point in the middle goes in.
It can also be tightened.
Do you understand?
In fact, it is the same as making pants.
It's just that a person's pants is a point on your hip.
Then the knee is a point.
Then making clothes is a point on your waist.
Then the waist is a point.
There is a point here at the bottom.
Do you understand?
So when you change it, you still have to pay attention.
Don't change a whole line.
Add more points and adjust them.
In fact, in the end, we put the back here and flattened it.
Let's take a look.
This is our last waist here.
Flattened.
Then the bottom is also flat here.
There are two relatively small, not obvious wrinkles here.
You will see that your shoulder is actually straighter here.
Add a line.
The manual top should be around his top.
Yes.
So you can do less of a line.
In fact, it will be more convenient to do less of a line.
Because my friend asked me before.
Say.
I feel that the top will be a little troublesome after I tighten it.
It really is like this.
So we.
So when we are doing the suit.
The middle piece of the suit is just the same.
It is also a separate piece of board.
You can separate the top like this.
Then let's take a look at how to do the fork.
If you do the fork.
In fact, it is the same as the sleeve.
We first find a straight point here.
Add a straight point.
After the straight point.
Select this line.
Select the panel line expansion.
So we have a lot of this amount out.
After we have a lot of amount out.
Let's take a look at how to do this fork.
First of all, here in the back.
We will sew up more than the fork first.
After sewing it together.
We can freeze the other unimportant panels.
Then the two panels of the back are activated separately.
In order to prevent everyone from not understanding why I can start to make mistakes now.
I don't care about that panel.
It's because we checked it out little by little just now.
The problem is actually our back.
The line of the back of the back.
The line here in the middle of the back.
It affects other parts.
So we just go little by little.
To make the back flat.
Understand?
What about the recording?
It should be on Sunday.
After I go to work on Sunday.
After editing it.
It will come out.
Okay.
Then we start to do this fork.
If you do the fork here.
You can see.
Because our panels are symmetrical on the left.
So if you use the folding arrangement tool.
Is it upside down on both sides?
But the fork is not upside down on both sides.
Let's take a look at the structure of the fork.
How to do it.
First of all.
We can cut and sew the panels first.
In this way.
It's easier to control this single panel.
Okay.
After controlling it.
This panel.
Use the positioning tool to adjust it.
Then put these two panels together.
Cut them off.
It will be very convenient.
For us to do the fork.
Finally, it's good to merge them together.
Okay.
After the final merger.
We put these lines of the fork.
All that should be created is created.
Okay.
First of all.
Here.
We turn it over.
Fold it.
After that.
Create the powder line.
After creating it.
Open the simulation.
In fact, this fork has been folded.
Let's come again.
In order to prevent everyone from understanding.
Let's talk about it again.
What is this fork?
First of all.
This fork.
We cut these two panels down separately.
Next.
Let's turn this piece in between.
Turn it over.
This is the fork.
We already turned it over.
Okay.
After turning it over.
Hide it.
In another piece.
Inside.
Then we push this piece of board in.
But it's tied to another fork.
And this.
In the middle of this back piece.
Then put them together.
The two pieces.
Side.
Coated together.
After it is coated together.
We are a little bit.
To get an idea of where they are.
Then press the control key to simulate.
Now we have this fork.
After it has been installed.
by the fork.
The top of the fork should be sewn up, or the fork will slip out.
Which one? Which one?
Okay, sew it up here.
After sewing it up, because they are foldable,
in order to prevent instability, you can change the type of sewing line.
Then about the side here,
will the fork slip out by itself?
This is because we haven't modified its folding angle.
So we have to use the editor sewing line tool to select the sewing line,
and then modify its folding strength.
And then when we modified the folding strength just now,
did a problem occur?
This fork, its folding strength, because they are symmetrical plates,
so the sewing line will slip out.
The folding strength of the folding line will modify each other.
That is, I modified this side, and this side will also modify at the same time.
So I cancelled the connection between these two plates.
Because the fork is tilted to one side.
The fork is generally tilted to one side.
That is, the structure of this fork is like this.
This fork, for example, here should be a line of 180 degrees,
and then push it over.
Let's take a look at the last file.
Of course, I did a test.
In the end, I made a side difference.
It's actually tilted to this side.
It's like this from the bottom.
Do you understand?
So the folding of our left and right is different.
Because this line is 180 degrees, it is parallel.
Then in the middle, this position in the middle,
it is facing the front.
So the folding angle of this line in the middle is 360 degrees.
Then the fold angle of this line on the outside is 0 degrees.
Then let's simulate it together.
Then everyone will definitely say,
why should I make a fork here?
First of all, a lot of suits actually have forks.
If it has a fork, it can be done while the waist is very close.
In general, this suit is also close.
Then in some riding horses or archery,
in the case of these intense sports,
it has enough material to let you go to exercise.
Otherwise, if you are dead, there is no difference.
You do some more special actions.
Because suits, they are generally not very strong in stretching.
It is still more suitable.
If you do some intense sports,
especially your hips and hips,
you may be able to run when the exercise is relatively large.
So I will add a fold to it.
It's convenient for you to exercise.
Do you understand?
Add a fork.
In addition to the back center,
the side can also add a fork.
If you don't add a fork to the back center,
you can sew the back center together.
After sewing,
we go to the side and do it in the same way.
Also add two straight lines,
then expand the outer edge of the board.
Let's speed up here.
This is the same method.
The board is expanded.
It's just that if the side is bad,
you don't need to open as much as the back center.
Then try to print the board.
Then fold the board.
It's the same as the back center.
Let's skip here.
This is the same as the back center.
Then fold it.
Let's skip here.
In the process,
you can print the board more.
Because if you print the board,
you can apply the folding angle of the back center line
or the folding angle of the inner line
more quickly.
Then don't forget
the rules for setting the folding angle.
The rules for setting the folding angle.
Because when we do the side bulge,
sometimes,
because of the structure of the butt,
the side bulge is easy to open.
If it's not beautiful
if it's not beautiful,
we can use the sewing line
to sew the two ends a little bit.
After sewing a little bit,
we can also
make the sewing line longer
according to the need.
So that the side bulge
won't be too wide.
Understand?
Okay,
I'll think about it later.
What should we change next?
Oh, I remember.
Next,
it's about the structure of the waist.
In the MV,
we can see that
there is a structure
of the waist
in the back of the clothing.
There will be one in the shoulder.
Don't worry.
Because there are a lot of videos
that don't talk about it.
There will be one in the back of the shoulder.
In the back,
we are going to make a fold.
After making the fold,
you can see that we still have to change the inner line
of the waist.
After making the fold,
we will use the sewing line
to sew it up.
There will be a fold
in the movement.
This is something
that often appears
in the lining.
It is to add some folds
in the back of the clothes
to make the back of the clothes
more tight.
And there is enough volume
in the back of the clothes.
It is also to draw three lines.
But it is made
in the way of folding.
You can see that
when we reduce the volume of the chest,
its effect
is very obvious.
Then here
we use the sewing line
to sew the left and right together.
Here is the effect
of the fold we did before.
In fact, it is to draw
three inner lines
in the way of folding.
Just like this.
Let's apply the
inner line of the fold.
Then we sew the inner line
to the left and right together.
After sewing,
we can see that
there is a problem
with the sewing line.
There is a bent corner here.
We can actually do it in a different way.
First of all,
we stretch the inner line a little longer
and add some points in the middle.
When you add points with the X key,
you can choose the line
to be evenly divided
by the right key on the line.
After the line is evenly divided,
first of all,
we stretch the inner line
a little longer.
Then we adjust
the position of the sewing
a little bit.
This way,
the upper and lower lines
will be separated.
This way,
it will be more natural.
In addition,
there is another way.
We can make it like a rope.
We can make it like a zero-shape structure.
Because the zero-shape structure
is gradually shrinking
to one point.
So you can see
that when you make a zero-shape structure
and sew it together,
the focus of this transition
is on your waist.
In this way,
we can
get rid of the
very obvious structure
before.
Because if we used
three vertical lines
to sew together,
there will always be a strange point in the middle.
So we can finally
make a zero-shape structure.
In this way,
we can make a zero-shape structure
in addition to the
waist and pants.
But at this time,
do we find that
because this suit is more close-knit,
so when the suit is
on the outside of the structure
of the waist and pants,
there will definitely be a conflict.
At this time,
if we directly change
the number of other sheets
,
since we can't shrink
the inner sheet,
we can turn it over
and make the outer sheet larger.
So we are now
anti-activating other sheets
because we can't freeze other sheets
or there will be a conflict.
When anti-activating other sheets,
we can choose the outer suit
and then increase
their shrinkage rate
to 120.
After that,
we can compare
other sheets.
Of course, if you add 140,
it will be a little too big.
So we can increase it here.
For example,
you definitely want it to be wider
in the horizontal direction,
but in the vertical direction,
it doesn't need to be so wide.
Then we can choose
the inner sheet
and freeze these sheets.
Choose the outer suit jacket
and set it to 1.
So it can slowly
because this sheet is now very large,
so it can be worn
to the outer of the other sheets.
Then if there is an unstable place,
you can manually drag these sheets.
After manually dragging,
because the suit we are doing now
is relatively large,
so it doesn't matter.
This suit will soon be
covered with these socks
and pants.
Because the open and open sheets
sometimes
the sheets will turn over.
Because it has a set folding angle
and some sewing lines.
Here we can directly print the sheets
to solve these folding problems.
After that,
we put on the outer suit
because now the suit is already worn.
So we can slowly
reduce it to 100.
Remember to reduce it slowly.
Don't reduce it to 100 at once.
Otherwise, it may not be stable.
Understand?
Okay.
When we finally return it to 100,
this whole suit jacket
is already worn on the outside of the other sheets.
Next,
we are going to print all the sheets
and then remove all the sheets
so that they can return to normal.
Okay.
Because I was referring to the video
that I was referring to.
In the video,
when he was doing this kind of lining,
he might be wearing a relatively loose suit.
In the end,
he untied the button.
Here we first reduce the particle diameter of the sheet
and then reduce the conflict thickness a little bit.
Okay.
If you directly simulate it at this time,
you will find that I directly reduce
the impact of the conflict thickness.
Then I will separate it.
I first reduce the particle diameter a little bit
and then simulate it.
After it is simulated and stabilized,
we will reduce the other numbers.
Then if his button is unstable,
you can first
cancel
their machine
to remove
the machine between the button
and the buttonhole.
Because
I actually refer to
the MV.
Then in the MV,
he didn't send money.
I didn't send money to him in the end.
Then we reduce the conflict thickness
little by little.
Because just now
we reduced the conflict thickness
directly to 1,
it was unstable.
So here,
we will reduce it to 1.5
and then reduce it to 1.
Okay.
Then let him
the bottom of these places
are slowly simulated.
Then we will
reduce the particle diameter
to 10.
Okay.
After that,
we can use this line
line 3D board tool
to draw a pocket shape
on the board.
After that,
we can copy and paste
the whole board
along this position
or directly in the 3D space
choose the 3D line we drew
and then right-click
to switch to the internal shape
so that there is a linear internal line.
After there is a linear internal line,
we can select
these internal lines
and then cut the pocket board
out.
After cutting it out,
merge the pocket board,
the extra points
and the extra points
on the outside of the board
can be deleted.
Here,
if you want to know
about making a pocket,
you can watch the video
about making a pocket
by drawing this sewing line.
You have to pay attention
because some sewing lines
may not be connected
to some internal lines
and panel lines.
So we can press the Shift key
to sew between one section
and multiple sections.
After sewing,
choose to add it to the outside.
Okay.
After sewing,
there is a fixed section
of the inner line.
So here
we can create
an inner line
and the position
of the pocket is the same.
Okay.
After creating
this inner line,
we can sew
these two sections
together with the sewing line.
Okay.
You can see
that these are all
for fixing the pocket.
Then we create
a corresponding pocket
in the chest.
Okay.
Here we make a fake pocket
that is the same as the previous one.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
I know it's a little late now.
We are about to end.
I am going to make
the shoulder pad now.
In fact,
the shoulder pad is also
fast to make.
Go, go, go.
Okay.
This is also very
simple.
It's like sewing.
We can just skip it.
Okay.
Then we start to make the shoulder pad.
If we make the shoulder pad,
For Lolita, you can look at the previous episode of LoCoCo.
To be honest, Lolita is more related to the material of the sticker.
The way to make the skirt of Lolita,
Oh, first of all, here, because I found that the length of the shoulder line is not right, so I modified it.
Lolita is actually really simple.
It's just a pile of all kinds of fabrics.
I don't think it's difficult.
It's not that it's not difficult, it's just that its operations are usually repetitive operations.
Of course, if you want to watch it, I will think about it and I will do it.
It's just that there may be a lot of things to do next.
So I don't know when there will be the next live broadcast.
Okay, then we will follow your shoulder line.
That is,
I will refer to these two positions.
The main thing is to match it with its sleeve,
and then draw a curve like this as a shoulder line.
In fact, I have made Lolita.
That episode of LoCoCo is the same as Lolita.
That skirt, I think it's already a more complicated style.
There are also live videos that you can watch.
I think because I actually do it myself,
I think it's really simple.
So I don't think it's necessary to do something like that again.
Then we finish this.
Well, after the electric shoulder plate,
we freeze all the other plates,
and then reduce the particle diameter of the electric shoulder plate.
Then create a symmetrical plate,
use the free sewing tool to sew from the middle point to both sides.
Because we didn't cut the point before,
so we can know very clearly that the middle point is the position of the shoulder line just now.
So we refer to the position of this plate,
sew this painted electric shoulder plate and the two sides of the shoulder line,
which is the sleeve, here.
Yes, if you are interested in how to make this Lolita costume,
you can watch the previous and...
It should be the live broadcast of the collaboration with Annie Raiden last year.
The one called LoCoCo style.
Okay.
After we made the shoulder plate,
flip it over.
Now we have two shoulder plate plates.
You can also watch the tutorial video of Hanfu before.
Okay.
After finishing,
simulate it.
Sew it.
Here, when we open the single-sided display,
we found that this plate is facing the back,
but the problem is not big.
If it is facing the back,
because we need it to fold faster,
and it is sewn together with the sleeve,
so here we can give it a folding angle of the sewing line.
I use 360 degrees.
So it can...
It can be pasted tighter.
Okay.
You can think about folding this.
Folding...
Folding angle.
Okay.
And then the shoulder plate.
Because the shoulder plate is generally hard,
it is not easy to fold.
So we give the shoulder plate a new fabric,
and then increase the bending strength a little bit.
So the shoulder plate is a standard shoulder plate.
Okay.
Why do we sew the shoulder plate to the clothes?
It is also for convenience.
When we change the posture later,
the shoulder plate does not need to be rearranged.
Because in our software,
although there is a limited number of shoulder plate files,
but that shoulder plate file has to be sewn to the board,
it is inconvenient to sew to your own board.
So I recommend that you still use the same method as me,
which is to put your front and back pieces
along the position of the shoulder line and pin them together,
and then use the board
to create a shoulder plate structure like this.
To make it easier for everyone to see,
I changed the color of the shoulder plate to white.
Here we have two shoulder plates.
Okay.
Then we activate the outer layer of the shoulder plate,
in addition to the shoulder plate.
Then set the level of these shoulder plate layers to 1.
Then return the level to 0.
Because now our shoulder plate
has been successfully worn into the clothes.
Then we increase the conflict thickness of the shoulder plate,
so that it has the effect of the shoulder plate.
Do you understand?
Okay.
Then we will soon have the effect of the shoulder plate.
Because the shoulder plate is actually the most important thing.
It is the shoulder effect of holding the clothes.
So we sew this board in,
and then automatically wear it in with layers.
When you sew the shoulder plate,
you have to pay attention to this.
Why don't you give the shoulder plate a negative 1 here,
but give the suit a positive number?
This is because we have other clothes in it.
If you give the shoulder plate a negative 1 directly,
it will wear directly to the inside.
Because we don't set a negative layer for other boards.
So we have to figure it out at this time.
We want the clothes,
that is, the suit, to wear outside the shoulder plate.
So we just set the layer of the suit
as 1.
Then after we finish the shoulder plate,
we are going to start making the sleeve.
But here I found that
the shoulder plate is a little bulging.
In fact,
the reason why it bulges here
is because we set the folding angle before.
But I didn't find it at this time.
I still think it's strange.
I still think the shoulder plate effect
is so obvious.
Because in general,
when it is 4,
it may just have a little bit of a bulging effect.
In my video,
there is blood at the bottom left corner.
We all have a live broadcast.
Then we will make the sleeve first.
Because at this time,
I haven't found the seriousness of the matter.
It's also very simple to make the sleeve.
We copy and paste this sleeve plate.
Then we use the inner lining to do it.
Of course,
my friends will say,
why can't I just use a rectangular plate to do it?
I tried it myself.
I think it's faster and more convenient
to use the inner lining of the lining directly.
Then we merge it in the middle.
Then we use this free sewing tool
to sew this elastic band to the sleeve.
What is the elastic band?
The elastic band is actually to hold your sleeve up.
It looks like there is a little bulging effect on the sewing line.
Because you hold your shoulder up,
and then the sleeve is held up,
the sewing line in the middle
will naturally have a bulging effect.
Then these two elastic bands also give it,
we also set a layer for the sleeves.
So the elastic band will be sewn into it automatically.
So we have this.
Then we have a circle of this elastic band.
This is the small piece of the sleeve
that is hidden inside.
This is called the elastic band.
And its sewing line,
because it and the sleeve are stacked together,
they belong to one side.
So we are going to set the sewing line between them as Turn.
The type of sewing line is set as Turn.
Then the elastic band can also be applied to it.
This conflict thickness is 3.
You can see,
the elastic band,
although we applied the conflict thickness to it,
but it only holds up a little bit.
Okay, at this time,
I found a problem.
I thought,
what's wrong with the sewing line of this sleeve?
Then I thought about it later.
It's my sleeve here,
the sleeve here,
I didn't use the elastic band for it.
Then I added the elastic band to it.
Okay, first of all,
you may ask,
what is the elastic band?
The elastic band is like this.
When you give a line,
after using the elastic band,
this line,
it won't transform because of the pull of other pieces,
or its own weight.
It will maintain its effect in the lower two windows.
It will try to maintain the effect in the lower two windows.
What does it mean?
It means that it won't pull because of the sewing line.
In fact,
it is equivalent to the part,
the part,
that is,
a line cannot be stretched.
Yes,
it is a bit similar to the meaning of the hard edge.
It is the same as the proportion of the elastic 100%.
This edge,
it can't transform.
Let's take a look.
What will happen if you apply the stitch line?
Have you seen it?
Soon,
your sleeve will stand up.
Have you seen it?
It will have a kind of,
along this,
along this sewing line,
this edge becomes very tight.
It is because it won't transform because of the stretch of the sewing line.
Then I will explain to you what is called the stretch of the sewing line.
For example,
you sew a line,
a short edge and a long edge together.
In our software,
or in real life,
in normal circumstances,
the board will be stretched by this sewing line,
left and right,
evenly stretched.
What does it mean?
That is,
the short edge will become longer,
and the long edge will become shorter.
This is the setting.
But if you apply the stitch line to the short edge,
then the short edge will not change,
because it maintains its original shape.
But the long edge will shrink more.
Because you used to take a 10-cm long edge,
and sew a 20-cm long edge.
In the end,
this line may be 12 or 13 centimeters.
But if you apply a stitch line to the edge of the 10,
then it will only have 10.
It will not transform because of the stretch of other boards.
Understand?
But this change,
this degree of transformation is not easy.
The degree of transformation is based on the physical properties of this stitch line.
So here,
I will show you how to do it.
First,
I will change the physical properties of this stitch line to undercollar.
You can see that the strength of the tail,
the strength of the gold thread,
and the strength of the right-angled thread are relatively high.
The tail is horizontal,
and the gold thread is vertical.
In other words,
it is suitable to be used in the sleeve.
Although it is called undercollar,
it is in the collar,
but it is also suitable to be used in the sleeve.
Because it is vertical,
it is not easy to stretch in the vertical direction.
So it is easy to maintain its original shape.
Because in general,
the sleeves may be larger than the sleeves.
Can you understand?
If you still can't understand,
I can show you a case later.
But let's continue to look back here.
Here,
after I add a stitch line,
you will find that,
the edge of the sleeve has become darker.
But,
at this time,
I remember,
ah,
I set a folding angle of the sewing line before.
Because at that time,
I think it shouldn't affect other parts.
Then here,
we need to adjust it.
First of all,
my shoulder part just now,
it is facing the back.
Because my sewing line,
the result of the sewing at that time was facing the back.
So at this time,
the first thing I have to do,
is to choose this shoulder part,
and then turn it over.
So that it is facing the front.
After it faces the front,
this sewing line,
we don't need to set a folding angle for it anymore.
Instead,
we directly change its sewing line type to what?
Change to turn.
Because it is folded up.
It and the sleeve are,
it and the sleeve are,
that is,
it is folded up.
Then,
now,
if there are some unstable problems of the grid turning,
we will add it again to the inside,
so that it can refresh.
Okay,
after refreshing,
turn on the simulation again.
Okay,
now our shoulder here is very flat.
And this shoulder has no problem with the previous one.
Can you understand?
Because what we used before was this,
what we used before was custom angle.
But,
we used 360 degrees,
which is the fold in the inside.
This will lead to this line,
it will identify the fold angle.
Then,
it may have some stretching problems.
In short,
the method we are doing now is right.
It is normal to sew this shoulder to the inside of the board,
and then set its sewing line to the sewing line type of turn.
Okay,
then,
because the layer level has been identified and stabilized,
so we can return the layer level to zero.
Actually,
we can use the same method to modify the pattern,
so that they can solve each other.
After solving,
we can start to change the action.
Because when you go to this setting,
when you set the stretch line,
your sewing line over there,
we still,
do you remember?
When we changed it before,
when we didn't change the sleeves,
this sewing line was very beautiful.
So,
after we add the stretch line along the sewing line,
the overall shape looks very good.
It's more even.
Okay,
here,
I actually pulled a speed.
Because I press Shift X,
and then change the action.
I'm looking at what kind of action will be changed in the end.
It's better.
Originally,
I wanted to do this.
Well,
because what I did was the one with the collar,
the one with the rice color.
So,
I actually wanted to do a
action of looking at the flower pot.
Later,
I thought about it,
because I personally like the content related to magic.
I just want to say that I can change its posture to
holding a magic hat on my hand,
and then holding a rolling pin effect behind it.
Okay,
then I changed its action a little bit.
Of course,
everyone is outside,
different actions can also be done.
If you use FBX,
you can directly press Shift X in Marvelous Designer,
open the editor Google,
and then adjust Google.
Can it slowly restore the original posture?
Yes,
your original posture,
as long as you have that FBX,
that is,
as long as you have that file,
you can do it.
Let me tell you what this logic is.
There are two situations.
The first situation is that you have FBX,
you have FBX files,
and it has Google,
then it's very convenient.
Because you can save this FBX file in the software
as an AVT format,
which is Marvelous Designer,
which is Marvelous Designer's unique virtual model format.
In this way,
you can repeatedly change its action in Marvelous Designer.
Yes,
and then you can choose to save it as a posture in the upper left corner.
Then,
in the form of loading the posture,
you load the posture in the form of loading the posture,
it can slow down,
rather than Ctrl Z return,
Ctrl Z return,
then there is no way to return together.
You have to press it again,
and then the material will return to the original look.
Understand?
But if you are an OBJ file,
then you have to use morph target,
that is, you have an A-pose OBJ,
you have to define it as a virtual model first,
and then you import it as a virtual model.
Then you import the second one,
which is also an OBJ,
and it is an OBJ with the same face number and top number as the previous model.
When importing,
download the type and select morph target.
Then in the previous virtual model related video,
there should be an award.
There is an award on the right,
then don't use that.
It is better not to use that.
When to use surface flip,
when to use positioning ball flip.
If the surface is flipped,
it is to reverse the direction of a board.
But if you use positioning ball flip,
its direction of direction will not be flipped.
That is to say,
it's not going to flip along its line.
If you choose to flip a board on the surface,
its line will actually be changed along with it.
Because its direction of direction is reversed.
But if you use positioning ball to turn in 3D space,
it's just a re-arrangement of the board.
It doesn't involve the rotation of its direction of direction.
Okay.
Then let's get into this action.
In fact, it's basically at the end.
But there is a section behind here.
A short video.
Why?
Because in the process of our change of action,
you can see,
I also deliberately put this section for everyone to see.
When we change the action,
sometimes your action
accidentally encounters these relatively loose positions.
It will pull this fabric back, right?
First, let's learn here.
How to deal with such a problem.
First of all,
you can see,
as we slowly simulate,
it's not a big problem for pants.
Pants have their own weight.
It's more flexible.
It can slowly return up.
But our suit here,
and the shirt,
and the vest are affected.
Right?
Then we have to deal with this problem little by little.
First of all,
we first choose the anti-activation board and the sewing line.
The suit in the back is anti-activated.
We have to look inside first.
Where did its problem come from?
Okay.
Then we hide the outer layer of the suit.
Let's look at this vest.
First of all,
the vest has been hooked by this finger.
So the vest here,
in fact,
there is already a problem.
Then we use the selection grid tool.
Don't forget that the vest has two layers inside and outside.
So we choose these two layers of grid at the same time.
Then use the selection move grid tool
to put these two grids together.
Then we use the selection move grid tool
to move these two grids together.
Okay.
In the process of moving,
we will see that the vest and the shirt
still have some differences, right?
There is still a difference.
So here,
no matter how we adjust it,
it is still a little unstable.
Then here,
we will give this back vest
a new layer.
After the layer is finished,
wait for it to slowly simulate stability.
Then here,
in the process of simulation,
you will see that
this electric shoulder has some conflicts with it.
So we have to give the outer layer of the vest
a layer that is higher than the vest.
That is, the layer is 2.
So it can be identified outside the vest.
So let's simulate it a little bit.
After we see that the vest has started to stabilize gradually,
we will return the layer to 0
and solve the shape hardening.
Before, when I was making this vest,
I gave it a shape solidification.
Shape solidification, not hardening.
Shape solidification.
When I gave it a shape solidification,
I wanted to keep the wrinkles on its back.
I think the wrinkles I adjusted are more beautiful.
Now that we have changed the movement,
we no longer need to maintain that shape.
We just need to solve the shape solidification.
Here you will find that
because we set the layer,
so between the sheets and the sheets,
it is particularly unstable
when the difference between the layers is severe.
At this time,
we don't need to solve the shape solidification anymore.
We just put the outer layer of the vest
all back to the fire version.
Finally, we put the vest on again.
When we simulate the vest,
we will find that it has some unstable problems.
Let's simulate it again.
When it is stable,
when all the inner structures of the vest
are stabilized,
we add the vest.
In addition,
we need to reduce the surface rigidity of the model.
because the previous surface rigidity
was 0
and the previous surface rigidity was 1.
You can see that
when the surface rigidity of the model was 1,
the first cloth was very close to the board.
In this case,
because its air thickness is thick,
it may affect
So let's reduce the surface diameter a little bit, and then after the clip is now simulated and stabilized, the level of the clip is also reduced to 0.
As for why the level, you may think that I set the level of the jacket as 2.
Why is the jacket set to level 2 and it is still different from the clip?
That is, when your clip is already unstable and shaking, does it sometimes have cracks or its surface will turn over and over again?
At this time, when it has a gap between it and other clips, it needs to identify its own instability and apply this layer, which makes it more unstable.
So after we have processed the other parts and stabilized them,
we finally go to the next step.
Put this suit on.
Okay, let's freeze the inner layer first.
After freezing it, we have already worn the inner layer.
Don't activate them again.
Don't let them participate in the simulation.
It will only be more unstable if you participate in the simulation.
Okay, then we put this clip.
Because the clip is stuck in the middle, the level of the clip is set to 2.
Then the level of the suit is set to 3.
Then the clip in the middle,
we can see it just now.
You can see that the clip is not in the middle of these layers.
So let's reactivate the clip.
Because it may affect some of the structure.
After it is reactivated, we will manually adjust the suit layer.
Okay, it's the same.
Here, we choose the grid tool.
Pull this part of the grid down directly.
Okay.
Okay, after pulling it down, it will slowly simulate it.
Okay, after the simulation is done, we will activate the clip and simulate it together.
Why do we activate the clip now?
Because sometimes it may be between the clip and the clip.
Because when the clip is frozen, it cannot be deformed.
In this way, the other clips are pressed outside it.
It may be that the space between the hand and the clip is not enough for the suit to pass through.
So we may simulate it together.
Also, the clip on the inside will also be simulated together.
See if there is an unstable problem with the insertion.
So in fact, to solve the insertion problem of such a clip,
you must be patient to solve it layer by layer.
Okay.
Let me see how I solved it in the end.
In my impression, it seems that I chose the back-activated clip at the end.
Then I added a shrink to the shirt inside the vest.
Let it tighten.
Because there is too much fabric in the shirt inside.
It doesn't...
It holds up the entire back.
There is not enough space for me to put the suit.
So I decided to put the inner layer of the clip on them first.
This shrink.
Let them become a tight structure.
Then put on the suit.
This kind of action should not be animated, right?
Well...
If you wear it with your hands,
it will be more troublesome.
Because your hands will hook to the plate.
But if you do animation settlement,
first of all, you can see that I added a shrink to the inner layer.
After becoming tight,
there is space between the hands and the back.
Wear this suit.
After I wear this suit,
I can put on the suit first.
After wearing it, I put the shrink back gradually.
It's still the same.
Make the inner layer tight.
Then if you do animation settlement,
be sure to reserve space.
And then I found that the middle of the plate
may be hooked to the hand.
At this time, you have to intervene in advance.
Oh, I'm not Korean.
I'm Chinese.
Well...
Okay.
Then...
Then here,
we can see that
when I have all the plates inside
shrinked and frozen,
Okay.
We can activate the outermost plate.
After activation,
because there is more space inside,
you can put it.
This plate will wear it by itself.
After wearing it,
first anti-activate the buckle.
After making the entire suit jacket flat,
we will activate the tree belt again.
Okay.
Then at this time,
because my hand movement may be exaggerated,
the button here is a little unstable and shaking.
Let's untie this button first.
Don't make the button thin.
Because the button itself,
if you participate in the simulation,
activate the activation,
that is, activate the conflict,
it is indeed,
sometimes there will be some instability and impact.
Then here,
we let it simulate a little bit.
After the simulation,
you can add a little needle to this collar,
and then adjust the position of it.
Okay.
There is also this,
the point where the edge is pointed,
we can hardening it.
Okay.
First of all,
in order to prevent the layer to be unstable,
basically,
if the clothes are generally more stable,
in this case,
you can change the layer to zero.
This is also what we often ask in the group,
that is,
a lot of people ask the question,
that is to say,
hey,
why is my clothes always unstable?
But in fact,
you have to know that your instability,
sometimes it is very likely that it is because you have added a layer,
rather than saying that after you add a layer,
how can it be unstable?
In fact,
sometimes you remove this layer of application,
but it is more stable.
No need,
I think,
that is,
you can have a little concept,
it is not that you have to learn fashion design,
because there are a lot of linear things on the Internet,
and in our software,
there are also linear clothes in the modular controller,
you can,
you can totally refer to these linear clothes,
and you can usually pay attention to our,
this official channel,
those videos,
if you are a newcomer,
you can start from making dresses,
a relatively simple structure like a half-body dress,
start learning,
and the previous one,
I made a video of Hanfu,
because the Hanfu is also a relatively simple structure,
good,
and then we can use a sewing needle here,
because the collar here is frozen,
if you use a sewing needle,
you can fix the collar,
so that it does not spread too wide,
and then I print the back piece,
it is also to make it convenient to organize this side,
this folded pleats,
here is the folded tea,
first we can reverse the fire,
this sewing needle,
and then go back to this tea,
to organize it,
because that side is normal,
this side,
we can manually drag the board,
and then let this tea,
we can put this tea,
where it should be folded,
to drag it in,
when necessary,
we can add some fixing needles,
to fix the position where it is,
good,
and then wait for it to simulate,
it's okay to hammer it down,
good,
and then we just fire the powder line,
it's okay,
and then the rope here,
because we just had some instability,
something,
it is very likely that these ropes,
that is, we,
I used to call this fold,
ah,
these ropes,
may be,
some instability,
ah,
or fold out,
so I temporarily put those powder lines,
all deleted,
in the end,
you can sew these powder lines back,
and then fire a tree egg,
good,
that basically now,
the overall structure is very stable,
after that,
we can put the inner layer,
this shrink,
out again,
and then the outer layer,
you can remove the hardening first,
and then simulate it,
good,
and then this shoulder pad,
can give it,
use it,
well,
to re-improve,
this conflict thickness,
to improve,
and then put the inner layer,
the vest,
and the shirt,
these shrink,
can return to 100,
that is,
the shirt at the very bottom,
ah,
if you can't see it,
you can put this shirt,
the shrink,
just increase it to 90,
you don't have to increase it to 100,
ah,
increase it to 100,
it may be,
this fabric may be too much,
it may affect it,
good,
and then here,
the pocket,
I was going to do it,
for a decoration,
in the end,
I wanted to say,
on his pocket,
add two pucker pads,
so I changed it again,
his powder line,
well,
then activate all the panels,
ah,
here,
I found,
ah,
his collar,
here,
may be,
because there are some stretch marks,
so I choose,
anyway,
it's all done,
I will,
ah,
return to the time,
there is no defrost,
ah,
the collar here,
frozen,
and then use the fixing needle,
to adjust,
his,
this,
collar,
position,
good,
then,
everyone,
using the fixing needle,
he,
when using the fixing needle,
must remember,
ah,
we first,
from the top,
down,
little by little,
is,
you have to,
let this clothes,
after using the fixing needle,
it looks,
the whole is natural,
ah,
let his curve,
is,
the transition,
a little more smooth,
good,
in fact,
add the fixing needle,
then,
everyone,
this is also a coincidence,
is to add more fixing needles,
to know,
ah,
what place,
and then,
where to drag,
here,
I actually,
with the fixing needle,
slightly,
to him,
adjusted a little,
as a result,
adjusted to the end,
I,
here,
after adding the magic hat,
I found,
the magic hat,
the collar,
to block,
I adjusted,
so long,
is,
to see,
my last,
final,
will see,
the final,
this result,
this magic hat,
made the collar,
a little more beautiful,
to let him,
is,
not so strong,
because,
in fact,
you,
this,
clothes,
is not,
when it is,
it naturally,
in fact,
will blow down,
but,
I hope,
it looks,
a little,
ah,
good,
and then,
we can,
freeze,
usually,
everyone,
when doing,
must have this habit,
ah,
between the levels,
to identify,
other times,
you can freeze,
ah,
most,
does not affect,
your adjustment,
part,
ah,
for example,
like me here,
I want to change my suit,
I freeze,
the vest,
pants,
and shirt,
here,
we add some,
fixed,
ah,
this board,
to pull flat,
ah,
this sleeve,
to pull well,
because,
here,
you put,
this,
button,
you do not put,
this,
untie,
button,
and eye,
ah,
you adjust here,
will be very troublesome,
so,
must remember,
ah,
if your sleeve,
here,
some unstable,
then,
we put,
his,
this,
button,
to,
untie,
do not let,
button,
and eye,
and then,
add a,
fixed,
this,
eye,
position,
to,
him,
cover,
when,
they,
cover,
then,
with,
the,
button,
and eye,
together,
and then,
delete,
all,
the,
fixed,
eye,
position,
is,
almost,
the,
button,
is,
a,
fixed,
position,
and the,
eye,
position,
is,
closed,
and,
under,
the,
eye,
position,
is,
a,
position,
and,
the,
eye,
position,
and,
the,
eye,
position,
and,
the,